Alexinder Virdee

Miami, FL | (954) 616-9029 | alex@virdee.com

alexvirdee.com | LinkedIn.com/in/alexvirdee/ | github.com/alexvirdee

Profile

I am a Miami based front-end developer with a passion for technology and software. I obtained my bachelor's degree at the University of Central Florida studying Business Administration. Programming as a hobby soon became a passion and after graduating I decided to pursue a career in software. It has now been two years i've been working in the industry with a focus on JavaScript web technologies. I am excited, and look forward to a new opportunity that will contribute to the continuous development of my programming skills.

Technical Skills: JavaScript, Angular, Express.js, MongoDB, SQL, Node.js, SPARQL, RDF, Ember, React, HTML5, CSS3, Grunt, AJAX, jQuery, Responsive Design, Tailwinds, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, Wordpress, Typescript.

Professional Experience

Web Application Developer

April 2018 - Present

INFOTECHSoft, Inc.

Miami, FL

- Web Developer tasked to the GeneTegra Platform Data Lakes and Baptist Health Projects committed to advancing biomedical research
- Utilized semantic web technologies such as SPARQL, RDF, and OWL to aggregate and query vast amounts
 of biomedical data
- Prepared and developed UX/UI mockup proposals using Balsamiq wireframing software
- Tasked with developing and enhancing features for company applications making us of the JavScript web framework Ember.js
- Worked through complex problem solving and fixed bugs as introduced
- Kept delegated software upgraded to latest versions and tested code with QUnit
- Used user input to develop, iterate, and ship applications in a swift efficient manner
- Skilled in the software development life cycle, improving overall quality of applications by using Jira project management software & Kanban methodology

Teaching Assistant

May 2018 - August 2018

University of Miami

Miami, FL

- Part time helped students grasp the basic fundamentals of programming in JavaScript
- Course covered the MERN stack | MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS

Education

Full-Stack Web Developer

Jan 2018 - Mar 2018

Ironhack

Miami. FL

• Ironhack is an immersive web development bootcamp with locations in Madrid, Barcelona, and Miami. The program has a fast paced setting with a highly selective cohort of students. (400+ hours)

Technologies learned: JavaScript, Angular 2, Node.js, MongoDB, Express, HTML, CSS, Sass, jQuery, Bootstrap, Git

University of Central Florida - Orlando, Florida

Aug 2012 - Aug 2016

B.S in Business Administration - Management, Entrepreneurial Track